[{"question": "This Des Moines actor went to Coe College and had roles in \"In The Line of Fire\" (1993) \"Remember the Titans\" (2000), and \"Old School\" (2003). He also had a role on the television series \"Baywatch.\" Who is he?", "answers": ["Gregory Alan Williams", "Don Ameche", "Elijah Wood", "Raymond Hatton"]}, {"question": "This Sioux Citian started as an animator later wrote the screenplays for \"The Little Mermaid\" (1989), \"Aladdin\" (1992) and \"The Princess and the Frog\" (2009) for Disney.", "answers": ["Ron Clements", "Chuck Jones", "Matt Groening", "Grim Natwick"]}, {"question": "Born in Stanton, she also lived in Des Moines and later attended Mediapolis High School in Des Moines County. This actor had roles in \"Johnny Tremain\" (1957), \"Judgment at Nuremberg\" (1961) and \"Guess Who\u00e2\u0080\u0099s Coming to Dinner\" (1967). She became known in the 1970s as Mrs. Olson in Folger\u00e2\u0080\u0099s coffee commercials, who is she?", "answers": ["Virginia Christine", "Lola Lane", "Hope Emerson", "Lillian Russell"]}, {"question": "West Des Moines born-author Peter Hedges wrote what novel that in its film adaptation starred Johnny Depp and Leonardo DiCaprio?", "answers": ["Whats Eating Gilbert Grape?", "Twilight", "The Hunger Games", "Avatar"]}, {"question": "Born in Cedar Rapids, this actor played Jim Hawkins in \"Treasure Island\" (1950) and voiced Peter Pan in the 1953 Disney film. He never overcame the typecasting of being a child actor and his career faltered. Who is he?", "answers": ["Bobby Driscoll", "Don Ameche", "Raymond Hatton", "Conrad Nagel"]}, {"question": "Many pre-1960, Iowa-themed films occur in rural settings but this 1957 movie starring Doris Day took place at a factory in Cedar Rapids. What is the film?", "answers": ["The Pajama Game", "Twister", "The Straight Story", "Keep Your Powder Dry"]}, {"question": "Appearing in a handful of films including \"Thirty Seconds over Tokyo\" (1944) and \"It Happened on 5th Avenue\" (1947), this actor from Cedar Rapids had a successful television career including 125 episodes on \"Hazel\" as George Baxter from 1961-1965. Who is he?", "answers": ["Don DeFore", "Ashton Kutcher", "Ron Livingston", "Elijah Wood"]}, {"question": "Born in Waterloo, this actor played the female lead in \"The Creature from the Black Lagoon\" (1954). Who is she?", "answers": ["Julia Adams", "Priscilla Lane", "Rosemary Lane", "Lola Lane"]}, {"question": "This silent film-era actor was born in Dubuque, who is he?", "answers": ["Frank Keenan", "Raymond Hatton", "Marion Morrison", "William Frawley"]}, {"question": "Who wrote \"State Fair\"?", "answers": ["Phil Stong", "Jane Smiley", "John Irving", "W. P. Kinsella"]}, {"question": "Charlie Chaplin selected this Oskaloosa-born actor with a bushy mustache to play roles in his films \"Modern Times\" (1936) and \"The Great Dictator\" (1940). Who is he?", "answers": ["Chester Conklin", "Conrad Nagel", "Don Ameche", "William Frawley"]}, {"question": "This Dubuque-born actor played supporting and leading roles in many films including \"Okay, America!\" (1932); \"Jezebel\" (1938); \"Ellery Queen, Master Detective\" (1940) and six others:", "answers": ["Margaret Lindsay", "Marilyn Maxwell", "Kate Mulgrew", "Hope Emerson"]}, {"question": "This actor appeared in \"Wake Island\" (1942) and other films and was born in Sioux City, who is he?", "answers": ["Macdonald Carey", "Conrad Nagel", "George Reeves", "Don Ameche"]}, {"question": "This Marshalltown actor had roles in \"Interiors\" (1978), \"A Change of Seasons\" (1980) and \"The World According to Garp\" (1982). Who is she?", "answers": ["Mary Beth Hurt", "Lara Flynn Boyle", "Margaret Lindsay", "Linnea Quigley"]}, {"question": "This Davenport-born actor is known as America\u00e2\u0080\u0099s Scream Queen:", "answers": ["Linnea Quigley", "Joan Freeman", "Priscilla Lane", "Lara Flynn Boyle"]}, {"question": "This actor from Clarinda appeared in \"Champion\" (1949) and \"The Lemon Drop Kid\" (1951) among other films, who is she?", "answers": ["Marilyn Maxwell", "Mary Beth Hurt", "Margaret Lindsay", "Mary Beth Peil"]}, {"question": "This author from Webster City who attended the University of Iowa wrote poetry and fiction. His work \"Glory for Me\" served as the basis for the 1946 film \"The Best Years of Our Lives.\" The movie received seven Academy Awards but he was disappointed that MGM Studios did not use his title. Who is he?", "answers": ["MacKinlay Kantor", "W. P. Kinsella", "John Irving", "Kurt Vonnegut"]}, {"question": "This Forest City-born actor starred as a singing cowboy but his career faltered and he was surpassed by other actors. Who is he?", "answers": ["Bob Baker", "Hoot Gibson", "Gene Autry", "Roy Rogers"]}, {"question": "This Sioux City-born actor was known for her singing and starred in multiple films including \"Laugh It Off\" (1939), \"Las Vegas Nights\" (1941) and \"Atlantic City\" (1944).", "answers": ["Constance Moore", "Virginia Christine", "Hope Emerson", "Joy Hodges"]}, {"question": "This Des Moines actor had a successful career and also purportedly told Ronald Reagan \u00e2\u0080\u009cto ditch the glasses\u00e2\u0080\u009d to become an actor. She later attended many White House dinners after he became president.", "answers": ["Joy Hodges", "Hope Emerson", "Constance Moore", "Kate Mulgrew"]}, {"question": "What year was the motion picture rating system including G, M and R established? (The M later becomes PG.)", "answers": ["1968", "1999", "2010", "2014"]}, {"question": "This author from Fort Dodge wrote the novel that became the film \"Mister Roberts.\"", "answers": ["Thomas Heggen", "W. P. Kinsella", "John Irving", "Max Allan Collins"]}, {"question": "The filmmaker from Carlisle and Des Moines Russell S. Doughten produced a well-known Christian film in 1972. Much of it was filmed in Des Moines, what was the name of the film?", "answers": ["A Thief in the Night", "Left Behind", "The Ten Commandments", "The Passion of the Christ"]}, {"question": "Who is the Fort Dodge-born film producer known for \"Wuthering Heights\" (1970), \"The Island of Dr. Moreau\" (1977) and \"The Amityville Horror\" (1979)?", "answers": ["Sam Arkoff", "R. L. Stine", "Stephen King", "Clint Eastwood"]}, {"question": "In what film did a Confederate Battle Flag fly on Terrace Hill, then a private residence, but today the Iowa governor\u00e2\u0080\u0099s home?", "answers": ["Cold Turkey", "The Music Man", "Whats Eating Gilbert Grape?", "F*I*S*T"]}, {"question": "This 1999 David Lynch film was based on the journey of Alvin Straights trip on a lawnmower from Laurens to Mount Zion, Wisconsin to visit his ailing brother. What is the name of the film?", "answers": ["The Straight Story", "The Final Season", "Sugar", "Michael"]}, {"question": "For what film did Hawarden native Hope Emerson receive a nomination for an Academy Award for her role as a warden in a women\u00e2\u0080\u0099s prison?", "answers": ["Caged", "State Fair", "Twister", "Stagecoach"]}, {"question": "This World War II-era film of 1944 shared the story of five Iowa brothers killed on the USS Juneau.", "answers": ["The Fighting Sullivans", "Tora! Tora! Tora!", "The Fighting Seabees", "Guadalcanal Diary"]}, {"question": "This Iowa actor had a role along with Arnold Schwarzenegger and Jamie Lee Curtis in the film True Lies. Who is he?", "answers": ["Tom Arnold", "Ron Livingston", "John Wayne", "Don Ameche"]}, {"question": "What Keokuk native moved to Des Moines as a boy and received an honorary Academy Award in 1940?", "answers": ["Conrad Nagel", "Donna Reed", "Cloris Leachman", "Thomas Hegge"]}, {"question": "Elijah Wood played the role of Frodo in this film:", "answers": ["The Fellowship of the Ring", "The Two Towers", "The Return of the King", "All of the above"]}, {"question": "This Iowa-born actor won a 2011 Teen Choice Award for his role in the film \"No Strings Attached.\" He  played the lead role in the 2013 film \"Jobs\" and is also known for his work on \"That 70s Show\" and \"Two and a Half Men.\" Who is he?", "answers": ["Ashton Kutcher", "Tom Arnold", "Brandon Routh", "George Reeves"]}, {"question": "What Academy Award-winning actor grew up near Denison?", "answers": ["Donna Reed", "Conrad Nagel", "Cloris Leachman", "John Wayne"]}, {"question": "What Academy Award-winning actor was born in Winterset?", "answers": ["John Wayne", "Cloris Leachman", "Donna Reed", "Conrad Nagel"]}, {"question": "What Academy Award-winning actor grew up in Des Moines?", "answers": ["Cloris Leachman", "John Wayne", "Donna Reed", "Conrad Nagel"]}]